today I am going to show you how to
approximate the Square t of 101 minus
the square < TK of 99 whenever you see
this type of question the first thing
you should do is rationalize the
numerator and in a minute I will let you
know why to do this multiply both
numerator and denominator by the square
root of
101+ the square < TK of 99 this way we
will have Plus in here instead of minus
using a + b * a - b as a s - b 2 the
numerator will be 101 - 99 or 2 and the
denominator will remain as it is so now
our job is to approximate this
denominator for that we will find the
integer numbers between which this sum
might exist let us call this sum as X so
we will try to find the integer value
which is just shorter than this X and
just larger than this x to do this we
will find the value of x² which will be
square T of 101 + theare < TK of 99
squar it will be 101 + 99 + 2 * the sare
< TK of 101 * theare < TK of 99 so using
this we have reduced these two ugly
square roots into a single square root
now 10 and 1 is 100 + 1 1 and 99 is 100
-1 so using this formula again we get
this value as 100 S -1 so x² will be 200
+ 2 * < TK of 100 S - 1 now how can we
get rid of this minus1 notice that 100 S
- 1 will be less than 100 square so x²
will be less than 200 + 2 * < TK 100 S
or it will be less than 200 plus plus 2
* 100 or 400 but 100 S - 1 will also be
much bigger than 99 Square so x² will be
greater than 200 + 2 * < TK of 99 s or
it will be greater than 200 + 2 * 99 or
398 so this part gives X less than 20
because 20 SAR is 400 and now if x is
greater than 398 then it is also greater
than 36 61 which is 19 squ so X will be
greater than 19 now our goal was to find
an approximate value of this one which
is
2/x since X is greater than 19 and less
than 20 so 2/x will be greater than 2
over 20 and less than 2 over 19 2 over
20 is
0.1 and 2 over 19 is
0.105 therefore our answer lies
somewhere between 0.1 and
0.105 so if we take their average we get
our answer as approximately
01025 now if we verify it using
calculator we find that we are really
close to our approximation so good